<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marie Perrot-Dockès</title>
    <link>/</link>
      <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Marie Perrot-Dockès</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 15:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Marie Perrot-Dockès</title>
      <link>/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title> Nouvelles bornes post hoc dans un cadre structuré</title>
      <link>/talk/ihp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/ihp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Les procédures classique de test multiples utilisent un seuil $\alpha$ définit à l’avance
et rejettent un certain nombre d’hypothèse en fonction de ce seuil sans laisser de liberté à
l’utilisateur sur le choix de ces hypothèses. Pour palier ces problèmes Goeman and Solari
(2011) et Blanchard et al. (2020) proposent des bornes post hoc. Dans ce cadre l’utilisateur peut choisir librement l’ensemble des hypothèses qu’il rejette et ce potentiellement
une fois l’étude effectuée et au vu des données. Les bornes post hoc vont donner une borne
supérieure du nombre de faux positifs dans l’ensemble des hypothèses choisi par l’utilisateur, tout en conservant des garanties statistique quelque soit l’ensemble sélectionné.
Dans cette présentattion nous verrons une procédure de contrôle post hoc en test multiples dans le cadres des
modèles de Markov cachés. La borne proposée utilise la loi a posteriori de la somme des
états cachés. Cette borne sera ensuite comparée aux bornes classiques par des expérience
numériques. L’objectif de cette étude est de proposer des bornes post hoc valident et le
moins conservatives possible pour étudier des phénomènes génétique, comme le nombre de
copies d’ADN le long du génome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Post hoc false positive control in Hiden Markov Models  for spatially structured hypotheses </title>
      <link>/talk/imt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 10:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/imt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embed your slides or video here using 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;
. Further details can easily be added using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Borne post hoc dans des cadres structurées en utilisant les modèles de Markov cachés</title>
      <link>/talk/rochebrune/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/rochebrune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embed your slides or video here using 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;
. Further details can easily be added using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Introduction to the post hoc false positive control</title>
      <link>/talk/gtt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/gtt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this presentation we study general linear model (multivariate linear
model) in high dimensional settings. We propose a novel variable selection approach
in the framework of multivariate linear models taking into account the dependence
that may exist between the responses. It consists in estimating beforehand the co-
variance matrix of the responses and to plug this estimator in a Lasso criterion, in
order to obtain a sparse estimator of the coefficient matrix. The properties of our ap-
proach are investigated both from a theoretical and a numerical point of view. More
precisely, we give general conditions that the estimators of the covariance matrix and
its inverse have to satisfy in order to recover the positions of the zero and non-zero
entries of the coefficient matrix when the number of responses is not fixed and can
tend to infinity. We also propose novel, efficient and fully data-driven approaches
for estimating Toeplitz and large block structured sparse covariance matrices in the
case where the number of variables is much larger than the number of samples wi-
thout limiting ourselves to block diagonal matrices. These approaches are applied
to different biological issues in metabolomics, in proteomics and in immunology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Méthodes régularisées pour l’analyse de données multivariées en grande dimension : théorie et applications.</title>
      <link>/talk/miat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 10:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/miat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this presentation we study general linear model (multivariate linear
model) in high dimensional settings. We propose a novel variable selection approach
in the framework of multivariate linear models taking into account the dependence
that may exist between the responses. It consists in estimating beforehand the co-
variance matrix of the responses and to plug this estimator in a Lasso criterion, in
order to obtain a sparse estimator of the coefficient matrix. The properties of our ap-
proach are investigated both from a theoretical and a numerical point of view. More
precisely, we give general conditions that the estimators of the covariance matrix and
its inverse have to satisfy in order to recover the positions of the zero and non-zero
entries of the coefficient matrix when the number of responses is not fixed and can
tend to infinity. We also propose novel, efficient and fully data-driven approaches
for estimating Toeplitz and large block structured sparse covariance matrices in the
case where the number of variables is much larger than the number of samples wi-
thout limiting ourselves to block diagonal matrices. These approaches are applied
to different biological issues in metabolomics, in proteomics and in immunology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Méthodes régularisées pour l’analyse de données multivariées en grande dimension : théorie et applications.</title>
      <link>/talk/irmar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/irmar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quantitative Multivariate Model of Human Dendritic Cell-T Helper Cell Communication</title>
      <link>/publication/tmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 16:40:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/tmod/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regularized methods to study multivariate data in high dimensional settings: theory and applications.</title>
      <link>/publication/these/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 16:40:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/these/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multivariate Th17 metagene for prognostic stratification in T cell non-inflamed triple negative breast cancer</title>
      <link>/publication/pic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 16:40:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/pic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo Academic&amp;rsquo;s Markdown slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code and math&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimation of large block covariance matrices: Application to the analysis of gene expression data</title>
      <link>/publication/block/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/block/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> A multivariate variable selection approach for analyzing LC-MS metabolomics data</title>
      <link>/publication/metabolomic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 16:40:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/metabolomic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variable selection in multivariate linear models with high-dimensional covariance matrix estimation</title>
      <link>/publication/jmva/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 16:40:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/jmva/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
